Guide to the Consumer Reports. Monte Florman papers, 1951-1979 RL.11858
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Monte Florman papers
1951-1979
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11858
5.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Monte Florman was an engineer who spent most of his professional career with Consumers Union and served as Technical Director during the 1970s. The Monte Florman papers include correspondence, memos, meeting minutes, publications, research reports and other materials. Topics addressed include automotive safety, lawn mower standards, microwave ovens, nitrates and nitrites, radiation and office safety. Correspondents include Ralph Nader and Scott Maynes. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General and Administrative Files; Washington Office Files
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Monte Florman was an engineer who spent most of his professional career with Consumers Union and served as Technical Director during the 1970s. Florman was born in New York in 1926 and attended New York University (BS 1945). He joined Consumers Union in 1948, first as Project Engineer and later as the head of the Appliance Division. He became Associate Technical Director in 1964 and served as Technical Director from 1971 until his retirement in 1979. He died in 2015.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Monte Florman papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports. Board of Directors records
Consumer Reports. Irving Michelson papers
Consumer Reports. Washington Office records
Collection Overview
The Monte Florman papers include correspondence, memos, meeting minutes, publications, research reports and other materials. Topics addressed include automotive safety, lawn mower standards, microwave ovens, nitrates and nitrites, radiation and office safety. Correspondents include Ralph Nader and Scott Maynes.
Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; Product safety; Florman, Monte; Nader, Ralph; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- General and Administrative Files, 1951-1979; 1
  - General Office Files, 1951-1979; 1
    - American Home Appliance Manufacturers, 1972-1978; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Board of Directors, 1972-1975; 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Board of Directors, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Board of Directors--Ralph Nader, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
    - Board of Directors--Scott Maynes, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
    - Center for Consumer Product Technology--Evaluation Panel, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Consultants, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Consumers Union policy, 1972-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Economic Impact of Proposed Lawn Mower Safety Standard, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Feasibility Study of Product Tests and Reporting for Handicapped Consumers, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Interoffice memos, 1969-1977 (Box 3)
    - Personal, 1951-1971 (Box 3)
    - Radiation, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - Search Committee for Executive Director, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Speeches, 1958-1972 (Box 3)
    - Standards, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Automotive Test Division, 1965-1973; 2
    - Automotive safety, 1971-1973; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Corvair, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Crash tests, 1965-1971 (Box 4)
    - General, 1971-1973; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Consumers Union and Government Agencies, 1971-1974; 3
    - Consumer Product Safety Commission, 1972-1974 (Box 4)
    - General Services Administration, Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
    - National Academy of Sciences--National Research Council, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce--National Business Council for Consumer Affairs, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - National Bureau of Standards, 1972-1974; 4
    - General, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Panel 11--Product Evaluation, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Panel 411--Evaluation Panel, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Product Evaluation Technology Division--Evaluation Panel meetings, 1972; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Washington Office Files, 1969-1976; 2
  - Appliance Division, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Automotive Division, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Division, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Foods Division, 1973-1974; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - James Brodsky, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Lowell Dodge, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Microwave ovens, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous legal, technical, testimony, 1972-1974; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous legal, technical, testimony, 1972-1974; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Nitrates and nitrites, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Peter Schuck, 1972-1974; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Requests, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Standards, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Textiles Division, 1973-1976 (Box 7)
  - Toy safety, 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Urethane, 1969-1973 (Box 8)